## **WESLEY "AUSTIN" EMBERLIN**

1011 NW 2<sup>nd</sup> St Abilene, Kansas 67410 | C: (405) 519-1206 | wesley.a.emberlin@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

Highly motivated, solution-focused, analytical professional offering a comprehensive data analytics background. Experience with supporting U.S. military operations in roles of increasing responsibility during an eight-year career in the United States Navy. Effective communicator who quickly masters new roles and technologies to achieve positive results. Current Full-time Data Analyst in the FinTech industry and full-time Engineering Technology - Machine Learning and Autonomous Systems undergraduate student at Kansas State University.

### **Highlights**

- College graduate with a 4.0 GPA
- Advanced Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Access
- HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap 5/PHP/MySQL/GitHub/XAMPP
- Database Design, Implementation, and Troubleshooting
- Agile Project Management with JIRA and KanBan
- 7+ years as a Data Analyst SME
- 6+ years of ESRI ArcGIS Experience
- Strong Communication Skills
- GIS Metadata Experience
- Microsoft SQL Server/T-SQL/MySQL

### Experience

Data Analyst 06/2022-Current Remote

- Extensive Microsoft Excel experience.
- Conduct analysis directly supporting a supervised regression machine learning model.
- T-SQL and R/R Studio experience.
- Managed 11 Data Analyst Interns.
- Demonstrated critical thinking, problem-solving, and communication skills.
- Use statistics and data analysis to produce data visuals.

# Police Officer (Part-time) Abilene Police Department

08/2021-Current Abilene, KS

- Demonstrated critical thinking, quick use of judgment, problem-solving, and communication.
- Displayed strong moral character, interpersonal skills, integrity, and communication skills.
- Exhibited resourcefulness, taking initiative, capacity for engaging in teamwork, and collaboration with multiple agencies and personnel.
- Required daily to solve unique or complex problems and explain my findings in a concise manner.

# Full-Stack Web Development Intern Team Lead Tatum Games

12/2021-03/2022 Remote

- Frontend and backend website development.
- HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap 5/PHP/MySQL.
- VS Code/GitHub/Git Bash/XAMPP/Agile Project Management with JIRA.
- Team Lead over six other interns.

Police Officer Salina Police Department 06/2019-08/2021 Salina, KS

# Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Data Analyst and Project Manager United States Navy (Active-Duty)

09/2015-05/2019 Wahiawa, HI

- Operationally worked for the National Security Agency/Central Security Service providing timely and accurate analytical support, knowledge, and assistance to the military cryptologic and intelligence community. Held a Top Secret/SCI security clearance with a polygraph.
- Supervised an organization of 24 personnel spread out between four different work centers to include five people on the 24-hour operations watch floor.
- Developed Standard Operating Procedures for all watch operations, analysis techniques, and reporting.
- Conducted analytical training and provided mentorship for junior intelligence data analysts. Created and maintained shift schedules and databases to track all work center operations. T-SQL experience.
- Primary subject matter expert (SME) for all intelligence data analysis operations in the organization.
- Conducted software design and testing for timely reporting of analyzed data reports to stakeholders.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, Word, and Access for intelligence data storage and reporting.

- Managed multiple projects with competing priorities simultaneously.
- Used basic statistics and data analysis to produce data visuals such as histograms, scatter plots, and other graphs to try and predict operations.
- ESRI ArcGIS program experience for mapping data layers allowing for high-level decisions to be made by decision-makers and stakeholders.

#### **Data Analyst and Technology Maintenance Manager United States Navy (Active-Duty)**

06/2011-09/2015 Mayport, FL

- Supervised operation and organizational maintenance of electronic systems and specialized equipment.
- Managed receipt, storage, and issue of logistical and ammunition processes.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, Word, and Access for intelligence data storage and reporting.
- ESRI ArcGIS program experience for mapping data layers allowing for high-level decisions to be made by decision-makers and stakeholders.
- Radio Frequency Electronic Systems Troubleshooting and Maintenance.
- Perform preventive/corrective maintenance on electronic warfare and electronic intelligence systems.

#### Education

B.S. in Engineering Technology - Machine Learning and Autonomous Systems Kansas State University – Salina Aerospace and Technology Campus Completed courses include but are not limited to:

08/2021-05/2024

3.76 GPA

- Calculus and Linear Algebra
- Database Systems
- Computer Programming (JavaScript, Python)
- Machine Learning and Autonomous Systems
- Systems and Software

- Geographic Information Systems
- Systems Administration
- Hardware and Networking
- **Professional Conduct & Ethics**
- Statistics

A.S. in Website Development Technology	08/2021-05/2023
Kansas State University – Salina Aerospace and Technology Campus	3.76 GPA
A.S. in General Studies/Criminal Justice	01/2017-05/2020
University of Maryland Global Campus	4.0 GPA
Extracurricular Activities  Vice President – Association of Computing Machinery – KSU Chapter	08/2021-05/2022

Member – Cybernetics Club – Kansas State University Chapter

11/2021-Current